To face a goblin king, courage is crucial. So for Scoob
and Shaggy, the odds are against them!
Scooby-Doo! and the Goblin King is a adventure,
animation, comedy film directed by Joe Sichta.
Scooby-Doo and Shaggy must go into the underworld ruled by The Goblin King in order to stop a mortal named
The Amazing Krudsky who wants power and is a threat to their pals: Fred, Velma, and Daphne.
Scooby-Doo / Fred Jones (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Shaggy Rogers (voice), played by Casey Kasem.
Daphne Blake / Cat Witch / Honeybee (voice), played by Grey DeLisle.
Velma Dinkley (voice), played by Mindy Cohn.
The Grand Witch (voice), played by Lauren Bacall.
The Goblin King (voice), played by Tim Curry.
Scooby-Doo!
and the Goblin King is a 2008 American animated comedy horror musical film, and the twelfth
in the series of Scooby-Doo direct-to-video films produced by Warner Bros.
Animation (though it used a Hanna-Barbera logo at the end of the film).
It was dedicated to Paulette Oates.
The DVD was released on September 23, 2008.
This is the first Scooby cartoon produced entirely without either one of
the original producers, William Hanna and Joseph Barbera.
The film explores themes of fairy, halloween, pumpkin, talking dog, duendes.
The tone is lighthearted.